Hi.
This is Henry Watson with the New Bern Fire-Rescue in New Bern, North Carolina.
In this segment, we're going to talk about the maximum working distance of the multi-use fire extinguisher.
The multi-use fire extinguisher has a working range of eight to twelve feet.
This is the starting distance that you would use to put out an ordinary combustible fire.
The maximum working distance is from eight to twelve feet.
Aim at the base of the fire.
If you're too close to the fire, then the extinguishing agent may cause the fire to spread.
Also, if you're too close to the fire, you may be burned, or the flames could change directions and cause you burns.
The maximum working distance is between eight and twelve feet, about the distance that I'm standing here.
Anything closer than that would cause the fire extinguisher to spread the fire.
Anything further away from this distance, the fire extinguisher would be ineffective.
It's important to remember the maximum working distance of the fire extinguisher that you're using.
In this case, eight to twelve feet.